#### Personal Details:

- Full Name: Agil Arya

- Date of Birth: 31 October 1995

- Address: 10 Watson Road, Muizenberg

- Email address: aqil.arya07@gmail.com

- Github: aqil07

- LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/aqil-arya

#### Education:

- Primary: SACS Junior School

- Secondary: SACS High School - Matriculated 2013

- Tertiary: Damelin College - Mowbray

• Graduated 2018 (Diploma IT)

# Professional experience:

# January 2021 - present

## Product Consultant at Kurtosys Systems Ltd

During this role, I have been exposed to;

- Leading a project end to end, from discovery to Production.
- Configuring components per the specifications on Confluence.
- Liaising with the client to gather information and translate those requests into user tasks to be implemented.
- Following the Agile and/or Waterfall methodologies during a project's lifecycle.
- Actively using Confluence and Jira.

## April 2020 - December 2020

## Implementation Analyst at Kurtosys Systems Ltd

During this role, I was;

- Engaging with Confluence and Jira.
- Implementing user stories according to the specifications defined.
- Creating document templates using Adobe InDesign.
- Configuring components per the specifications on Confluence.
- Querying API endpoints using Postman.
- Increasing my skill in TSQL.
- Learning additional languages such as JavaScript, XML, HTML.
- Exposure to JSON and learning to manipulate JSON objects using TSQL and JavaScript.

## January 2020 - March 2020

## Document Product Analyst at Kurtosys Systems Ltd

This role involved producing PDF documents such as factsheets and for reporting purposes. In this role, I was;

- Expanding on the skills I learned.
- Taking on more responsibility and independence.
- Writing TSQL queries.

## January 2019 - December 2019

## Associate Document Production Analyst at Kurtosys Systems Ltd

In this role, I was;

- Learning to troubleshoot TSQL code.
- Gained exposure to Talend Loaders.
- Gained exposure to SSIS and loading files via the SFTP.
- Understanding workflows.
- Gained exposure to API's.

# Skills

## Soft skills:

- Communication
- Peer support / training
- Adaptability
- Flexibility
- Teamwork makes the dream work
- Googling
- Troubleshooting
- "Sponge-Like" mindset when learning.
- Quick turnaround time
- Quality work output
- Process oriented

## Hard skills:

- SQL : 3 years
- NodeJS and Express. : 1 year
- React. : 1 year
- TypeScript : 1 year
- JavaScript : 2 years
- XML : 1 year
- HTML : 2 years
- Manipulation of JSON data structures using TSQL and JavaScript.: 2 years
- Postman: 2 years
- Building an API :3 years
- Using RESTful API: 2 years
- Talend Loaders: 1 year
- QA experience: 2 years
- GitHub & Bitbucket : 1 year

# Personal

## Personal Interests:

- Coding for fun.
- Classic Cars
- Surfing
- Hiking
- Animals
- Series
- Gaming

#### About me:

I enjoy solving problems and building cool things and getting to do those things with codes make it all the more exciting. I always strive to give 110% in personal and professional life.

During my professional experience, I have learned where my professional passion lies, and that is within the software/application development. Since realising this, I have found a particular interest in and enjoy using JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Node.js and Express.js. The reason I have chosen the above-mentioned items is because of what these technologies offer in terms of application and software development.

`Atwood's Law: "Any application that can be written in JavaScript, will eventually be written in JavaScript."'

Outside of work, I'll either be at home with my cats, with the family or in ocean. I do believe in having a proper work/life balance, even though I do admit, trying to maintain that balance is a challenge, but nothing that can't be achieved.